hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so today we are going to
discuss about a very common use case
which is called cross browser testing
now in tosa we already know how we can
execute our test cases on different
browsers so that can be easily done uh
by going into the test configuration and
then creating a test configuration
parameter choosing browser here and then
uh depending on what browser you want to
execute you can choose that particular
browser here so if I want to execute
this test case on Chrome I will choose
Chrome if I want to execute on Firefox I
will uh choose Firefox or any other
browser right so this is how you can EX
execute your test case on one single
browser each time you execute so every
time you execute you can change this
particular value from your execution
list or from your test case but what if
uh you have a requirement where you have
to run the same test case in multiple
browsers at the same time now this is a
popular interview question as well as uh
this could be a requirement in your
project right so rather than um having
different test cases which can execute
on different browsers you have to
execute the same test case in multiple
browsers at the same time so like all
other automation tools it is also
possible to configure it in tosa so
let's see how we can do this now I'll be
using this swag Labs login uh test case
for this particular demo and here uh we
have got a login process folder okay
which has got two steps open URL and
close
browser and what I'm going to do is I'm
going to copy this and I'm going to
paste it here so I will be having to
login process okay and the both login
process needs to be run on different
browsers okay now just for uh the sake
of differentiation I I will just remove
this Clos browser step from this login
process one and in login process two uh
it has got these two steps right so this
is an example where you have got two
different processes which needs to be uh
executed on different browsers okay to
verify that it is working as expected in
both the
browsers now uh we have got these two
different process now we can see how we
can run this in different browser ERS
from the same test case okay now instead
of uh providing a value like a constant
value for browser what we can do is uh
we can pass a buffer value here okay so
what we will do is we will pass uh
bore
browser okay so this is basically uh the
buffer name bore browser
okay and we are referring to the value
of bore browser so whatever uh the value
it will use the same value here in the
configuration parameter right now uh
what you can do here is you can have a
step here which is uh to um set buffer
okay and um inside this what we will
have is we will have the bore browser
buffer name and here we will pass the
value which is
Chrome okay similarly um I can have this
step again inside the login process
to okay this will be always the first
step and again bore browser but this
time around I will make it
Edge okay so like this you can have a
number of steps where you can set the
buffer to a different browser value
right and now what it will do is um it
will come here and it will set the
buffer to Chrome okay and then while
executing this test case it is going to
execute it on the Chrome browser because
in our test configuration parameter our
value is set to bore browser which is a
buffer so it is getting the buffer value
from the test case itself right and uh
similarly for the second process it will
pick up the value as Edge and it will
execute this uh particular login process
uh in the edge
browser so let's go ahead and see
whether uh this will work or not okay so
I'm going to run this in
scratchbook okay so this is the Chrome
browser which is the first step and now
this is the edge
browser
okay so here you can see uh the edge
browser was closed as per our login
process but the Chrome browser is still
running right so uh here um on the
scratchbook results or logs you can see
here the browser value was set to Chrome
in the first step and then it opened the
URL in Chrome and then here the browser
value was set to
Edge and then it opened the URL in Edge
and then it closed the browser uh which
is the edge browser tab right so this
way you can run your test steps in
different browsers from the same test
case you don't need to have different
test cases to run it on multiple
browsers or you don't need you have a
distributed execution for choosing
different browsers okay so this can be
done simply uh within your test Case by
just providing a buffer value in your
test configuration parameter which is
the browser
parameter that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video